<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<data>
	<heading>
		<h4>
			Career Timeline 
		</h4>
	</heading>

	<entries>
		<entry>
			<period>
				Autumn 2022
			</period>
			<head>
				Guest Faculty
			</head>
			<details>
				Indian Association for the Cultivation of Science, Kolkata.
				Course: &lt;a href=I2C/index.html&gt;Introduction to Compuuting&lt;/a&gt;
			</details>	
		</entry>
		
		<entry>
			<period>
				2022 - &lt;i&gt;present&lt;/i&gt;
			</period>
			<head>
				Associate Professor
			</head>
			<details>
				Institute of Engineering &amp; Management, Kolkata
			</details>			
		</entry>
		<entry>
			<period>
				2014 - 2022 (expected)
			</period>
			<head>
				Ph.D. (Defence Awaited)
			</head>
			<details>
				Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur
				&lt;i&gt;Research Area&lt;/i&gt; : LTE, Cellular networks
				&lt;i&gt;Supervisors&lt;/i&gt; : Prof. Arobinda gupta and Prof. Sandip Chakraborty
				&lt;i&gt;Thesis Overview&lt;/i&gt; : 
				Handover and Load Balancing in Dense LTE Network for Users in Vehicles -- Reduction in the number of handover is desirable for providing good quality of service. However in a densely deployed LTE network, for high-speed users, achieving this has its own set of problems. In this regard, we have provided some solutions published in reputed journal and conferences. During this time, I have gained experienced on i) identifying and modeling of problems, ii) designing experiments through technical analysis and iii) open-source tools.
			</details>			
		</entry>

		<entry>
			<period>
				2012 - 2014
			</period>
			<head>
				Software Engineer 2
			</head>
			<details>
				Citrix R&amp;D India Pvt. Ltd.
				&lt;i&gt;Responsibility&lt;/i&gt; :
				I had worked as a developer for an application virtualization tool called XenApp using C#, C++. I was responsible for fixing problems faced in deployed products by providing feature enhancements and bug fixes. During this time, I have gained experience in i) remote and local debugging, ii) distributed systems problems, iii) responsible coding and iv) communications. Also, on some occasions, I had helped in achieving a multi-party consensus. I had received a promotion from Software Engineer 1 to Software Engineer 2 within 1 year of joining.
			</details>	
		</entry>

		<entry>
			<period>
				2010 - 2012
			</period>
			<head>
				M. Tech (IT)
			</head>
			<details>
				Indian Institurte of Technology Kharagpur
				&lt;i&gt;Master's Thesis&lt;/i&gt; : Geospatial Services in Cloud Infrastructure
				&lt;i&gt;Supervisor&lt;/i&gt; : Prof. Soumya Kanti Ghosh
				&lt;i&gt;Thesis Overview&lt;/i&gt; : 
				Geospatial Services in Cloud Infrastructure -- In this work, using only open-source tools, we successfully deployed a first-generation IaaS cloud. We further demonstrated that data intensive geospatial services (e.g. WFS, WMS, WPS) can be safely deployed in a cloud environment by utilizing SaaS while respecting the privacy of multiple participating parties.
			</details>			
		</entry>

		<entry>
			<period>
				2006 - 2010
			</period>
			<head>
				B. Tech (CSE)
			</head>
			<details>
				West Bengal University of Technology
				&lt;i&gt;Bachelor's Project&lt;/i&gt;: Web Enabled Cluster Computing with Customized Load Balancing
				&lt;i&gt;Supervisor&lt;/i&gt; : Mr. Kalyan Mohanta
				&lt;i&gt;Project Overview&lt;/i&gt; : 
				Web-Enabled Cluster Computing with Customized Load Balancing -- In this work we provided a proof of concept that large computation can be remotely performed over commodity hardware and low-bandwidth connection by utilizing the Beowulf cluster and MPI.
			</details>			
		</entry>

		<entry>
			<period>
				2006
			</period>
			<head>
				Higher Secondary (XII)
			</head>
			<details>
				West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education
			</details>			
		</entry>

		<entry>
			<period>
				2004
			</period>
			<head>
				Secondary (X)
			</head>
			<details>
				West Bengal Board of Secondary Education
			</details>			
		</entry>
	</entries>
</data>
